Carlos Sabbah

Full-stack developer & Social media expert

Full-stack developer, Top tier influencer, and content creator with over 7 years of experience in the industry. Certified in advanced Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Front and backend), and in all major adobe programs including, Premiere, After effects, illustrator, Photoshop, and XD.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Viral Nation International

2019 - Present, Mississauga, Ontario

Head of the Social Broadcasters division

- I manage 12 Instagram and TikTok pages ranging from 50K to 1.5M+ in follower size, most of which I created. These pages collectively generate over \$200K+ in this division.
- I organize all relevant information via Google Suite to keep track of active campaigns, revenue, contracts and business information.
- I create content for the pages i manage and ensure there is effective growth, this includes, conversing wiith other influencers to stay on top of trends.
- I onboard influencers to our talent roster for future activations and maintain day-to-day communications with them.
- I create and run social media optimization workshops for creators in the official PUBG Mobile creator program.
- I successfully executed high level campaigns with brands like Intel, Facedrive, Plarium, Deal Dash, Playline, Gameloft, Zynga and Zynn.

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

Full-stack development

2022 - Present, Mississauga, Ontario

University of Toronto Full-stack bootcamp

- To push my capabillities in development, i enrolled in the University of Toronto Full-stack boot camp.
- In this Bootcamp (ongoing), I collaborate with other individuals and delegated a team to develop (currently) over 10 fully functional applications that each focused on different topics and development strucures.
- Some of the applications include a smart weather dashboard that operates using multiple APIs, a full-stack note taker application, node applications such as a SQL employee tracker, an E-commerce backend application, an MVC structured Tech blog and more.
- For all applications, i learned to work with Github's features such as issues, projects, branches and building effective repositories using best practices.
- I also learned to work with many development structures such as OOP, TDD, ORM, and MVC, as well as working heavily with git to perform many various commands.

Mississauga, ON L5L5C5 (647) 865 4606 carlossabbah@hotmail.com

SKILLS

Instagram, Facebook, YouTube and TikTok

Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects & XD

Python (Requests, Pydrive, Selenium, Tkinter, Panda, Gpsread, Beautifulsoup & more)

HTML (Fontawesome, TailWind, Daisyui, jQueryUI and bootstrap) and CSS

JavaScript (React.js, localStorage, jQuery, working with API, JSON, TDD, OOP & more)

Node.js (Express.js, Heroku, Sessions, Dotenv, Inquirer, MySQL, handlebars, Sequelize, ORM & MVC)

Github (issues, projects & more), Gitlab, Git, Insomnia & Postman

EDUCATION

New Media

Ryerson University

2013 - 2018 Toronto, ON

Full Stack Boot camp

Unversity of Toronto

2022 - Present Toronto, ON

carlossabbah@hotmail.com

React.is

2021 - Present, Mississauga, Ontario

Developing functional components

- I developed over 10 components with focus on different logic and functionalities.
- Some components including, Data Handling (Filtration, sorting and pagination), Fetching data from APIs (POST and GET), Dynamic and fixed Routing, handling form data, working with json and more.
- Additionally, i created components using Tailwind and Daisyui exclusively in order to maximize my skills using these frameworks.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

2021 - Present, Mississauga, Ontario

Web Development

- To pursue my passion for creativity and to improve my problem solving capability, i took advanced courses for all major front end development languages.
- Referring to mockups i created in Photoshop as well as from online sources, I developed over 11 websites, 5 of which are fully responsive and deployed.
- Additionally, i used bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery in my projects to add essential functionality as well as unique creative touches.

Python

2021 - Present, Mississauga, Ontario

Webscraping, Data Analysis and Automation

- In order to improve work efficiency, i took master python courses and developed a program that executes a part of my daily work routine.
- Further, i worked on other projects including working with fetched data from APIs, file management, automating data upload to google spreadsheet, image detection projects and more.
- Some of the libraries i worked with include Selenium, Tkinter, Panda, Tesseract, Requests, Pillow, Gspread, Numpy, Pydrive and more.

Marketing and Content Creation

2016 - Present, Mississauga, Ontario

Influencer

- During my studies at university, I created and grew a successful instagram page called @Likklelos6ix that surpassed 380K followers in a few months.
- I learned to use photoshop to create engaging content daily.
- Further, I took advanced courses to improve my creative skills, this includes, advanced adobe photoshop, illustrator, premiere, after effects and XD.
- This page allowed me to make extra income through paid promos, influenced my creative skills and taught me discipline by sticking to a consistent schedule.
- Overtime, I built multiple connections with other publishers and we collectively adapted with the algorithm.